Guide to the Yale University Native American Alumni Oral History Project
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Yale University Native American Alumni Oral History Project
2005-2008
WA MSS S-2610
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.25
(3 boxes)
The collection consists of eight videotaped recordings of Native American alumni of Yale University, recorded in November 2005 and November 2008, as well as paperwork documenting the project and its purpose. Interview subjects are asked to reflect on their student experiences at Yale University. Questions explore the interview subject's tribal background, experiences at Yale, college activities, perceptions of the University, and present employment. Each interview is conducted by an identified Native American undergraduate. Two recordings of events held during the 2005 Henry Roe Cloud Conference: A Celebration of Native Americans at Yale are also present. Running time of recordings ranges from twenty to thirty-five minutes.
Native American Cultural Center (Yale University)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Portions of the collection were transferred from the Yale University Native American Cultural Center/Yale College Dean's Office in 2008. Other portions were recorded under sponsorship of the Yale Collection of Western Americana for addition to the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research, but recordings for which no release has been obtained may not be reproduced. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Native American Cultural Center (Yale University)
The Native American Cultural Center was formally recognized by Yale College in 1996 to support and connect Native American students, faculty, and staff at Yale through programming, support services, and community facilities. The Center promotes a permanent and prominent Native American presence at Yale.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of eight videotaped recordings of Native American alumni of Yale University, recorded in November 2005 and November 2008, as well as paperwork documenting the project and its purpose. Interview subjects are asked to reflect on their student experiences at Yale University. Questions explore the interview subject's tribal background, experiences at Yale, college activities, perceptions of the University, and present employment. Each interview is conducted by an identified Native American undergraduate. Two recordings of events held during the 2005 Henry Roe Cloud Conference: A Celebration of Native Americans at Yale are also present.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged by year of recording session, then alphabetically by interview subject's last name. Related paperwork precedes each set of interviews. Two recordings of events during the 2005 Henry Roe Cloud Conference in New Haven, Connecticut have been placed at the end of the listing.
Indian students -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Interviews; Indians of North America -- Education (Higher) -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Video recordings; Bathke, John; Bernadette, Maya; Burns, Kathleen; De Zutter, Amanda; Garcia, Shandiin; Krebs, Allison Boucher; McNeil, Chris E.; Nelson, Joshua Bourne; Yale University -- Students -- Interviews; Native American Cultural Center (Yale University); Henry Roe Cloud Conference -- New Haven, Conn. -- 2005
- 2005 Interviews, Series I; 0.63; (1.5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Paperwork about interviews conducted in 2005 is followed by interviews arranged alphabetically by the last name of interview subject.
  - Administrative paperwork and documentation, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bathke, John (Diné / Navajo, B.A. 1993), 2005; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002091393901)
  - Burns, Kathleen (Nlaka'pamux, B.A. 1999), 2005; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002091393919)
  - De Zutter, Amanda (Mississippi Band of Choctaw Indians, B.A. 2001 and SOM 2006), 2005; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002091393927)
  - Krebs, Allison Boucher (Sault St. Marie Tribe of Chippea Indians, B.A. 1973), 2005; 1 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002091393935)
  - Nelson, Josha Bourne (Oklahoma Cherokee, B.A. 1996), 2005 November 29; 1 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002091393943)
  - Master recording of all 2005 interviews (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 2008 Interviews, Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Administrative paperwork and documentation, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bernadette, Maya (Tohono O'odham, B.A. 2008) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Garcia, Shandiin (Laguna Pueblo, B.A. 1997), 2008 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - McNeil, Chris E., Jr. (Tlingit-Nisga'a, M.A. 1975), 2008 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Other Recordings, 2005; Series III
  - Video footage of 2005 Henry Roe Cloud conference, New Haven, CT (1 of 2 mini DV), 2005 November 4-6; 1 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002091393950)
  - Video footage of 2005 Henry Roe Cloud conference, New Haven, T (2 of 2 mini DV), 2005 November 4-6; 1 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002091393968)